<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Initiative on Dravidian Culture &amp; Languages</title>
        <link>https://idclang.github.io/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Initiative on Dravidian Culture &amp; Languages</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://idclang.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>IDCL</title>
        <link>https://idclang.github.io/p/idcl/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://idclang.github.io/p/idcl/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://idclang.github.io/p/idcl/thumbnail.png" alt="Featured image of post IDCL" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author: IDCL Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to the Initiative on Dravidian Culture &amp;amp; Languages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initiative on Dravidian Culture and Languages (IDCL) aims to preserve and promote the linguistic and cultural diversity on India and beyond. The project has been established to improve the availability of resources and dedicate digital platforms for the enrichment of languages and cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The importance of language preservation has become a necessity in this age of globalisation. More than 3000 languages in the world are considered as endangered. This means that about half of the world&amp;rsquo;s linguistic identity is currently under threat. Linguistically diverse countries like India are struggling to conserve many of their indigenous languages. Major languages are driving minority languages into extinction, and the lack of effective government programmes are pushing these underprivileged communities into an identity crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, many interested individuals have come forward to take effective actions to protect their linguistic and cultural identity. Various digital platforms have proved to be a boon for these volunteers. However, due to a lack of resources and affordable tools, it is very difficult to efficiently deliver their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s see what we can do to preserve and promote these languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-resource-gathering&#34;&gt;1. Resource gathering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation can be in text, image, video or audio format. Recording the speech of native speakers helps is an effective way to document under-resourced languages. While the documentation in image format can be converted to text for further analysis. If possible, gathering resources from archives and converting them to digital formats is very helpful for language development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-preparing-educational-materials&#34;&gt;2. Preparing Educational materials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be done by either using the existing data or by establishing contact with the respective community. In either way, the beneficiary is usually the linguistic community. Educational materials can be prepared in two ways ;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;full documentation, which includes grammar, vocabulary, orthography etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;preparing educational materials for beginners or translating books (sciences, social studies etc.) from other languages to the target language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing digital tools such as software, translators and learning apps. Though this process requires a lot of resources and work, the end-user receives a lot of benefits. The accessibility and affordability of such tools make the conservation of the target language much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;volunteering&#34;&gt;Volunteering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;individual-projects&#34;&gt;Individual projects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This requires the collection of data, conversion of data into usable formats, preparing digital materials and publishing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;group-projects&#34;&gt;Group projects&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A group of volunteers contributing to a project in ways in which they can operate. This method reduces the workload, increases the overall performance, reduces the time taken to publish the final material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For enquiries, reach out to us through &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:dclprogramme@gmail.com&#34;&gt;dclprogramme@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/idclang/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; |
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC_xQ83x2V3Oj5uWfLbUK8Tg&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;
|
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;shttps://www.facebook.com/dclp.lang.3/&#34; &gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
